准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
匹萨外卖
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
赶紧把椅子擦干净  海绵宝宝
Hurry up with those chairs, SpongeBob
已经关门了
It's after closing
我要下班回家去
And I'd like to go home
我来接
I got it
来了
Coming
喂
Hello
先生对不起  我们关
Sorry, sir, we're closed
你好  蟹堡王
Ahoy, there, Krusty Krab--
需要什么服务
How can I help you?
匹萨
Pizza?
当然有匹萨了
Of course we have pizza
蟹老板
Mr. Krab
我们的章鱼外卖员马上给您送到
Our delivery squid will bring it right over
蟹老板  我们不卖匹萨
Mr. Krab, we don't serve pizza
匹萨
我们不外卖
We don't deliver
我们是不外卖
但外卖的是你
but you do
你就不能让海绵宝宝去送外卖吗
Can't you just get SpongeBob to do it?
好办法
Great idea
带他跟你一起去
Take him with you
我根本就不是那意思
That's not what I had in mind
船头
Front end
正常
Check
天线
Antenna
正常
Check
保险杠
Bumper
正常
Check
我为海胆踩刹车
保险杠贴纸
Bumper Sticker--
正常
Check
胎压
Tire pressure
正常
Check
车辆检查完毕
Vehicle inspection complete
我们真的要创造历史了  章鱼哥
We're really making history here, Squidward
那个幸运顾客
That lucky customer
就要领到史上第一个蟹堡王匹萨了
is going to get the first krabby patty pizza ever
很好  那就让你来开船
Good, then you drive
不能开
I can't--
我还在上驾校
I'm still in boating school
没事  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
开到这附近而已
It's just around the corner
确实  可是
Well, yeah, but
就照你在驾校里面学的做
Just do what you do in school
那
Well
好吧
Okay
等等  该不会是
Wait, don't tell me
倒车
Back it up
对
Right
倒车
Back it up
好了好了
Okay, okay
挂倒挡  海绵宝宝
Shift into reverse, SpongeBob
倒挡
Reverse
对  是倒挡
Oh, yeah, reverse
前进挡
倒挡
倒车
Back it up
方向盘给我  海绵宝宝
Give me the wheel, SpongeBob
方向盘给我
Give me the wheel
倒车
Backing up
好  你车倒完了
Well, you backed up
而且你知道吗
And you know what?
我们没油了
I think we're out of gas
油量
而且你还知道吗
And you know what else?
我们被困在荒郊野岭里了
We're in the middle of nowhere
你还还知道吗
And you know what else else?
我觉得匹萨要冷掉了
I think the pizza's getting cold
匹萨冷掉了
And the pizza's cold
The pizza's cold
匹萨怎么会出事
Not the pizza
这运气还能背到哪里去
How could it get any worse?
油量
起码还能走路去送
Well, we can still deliver it on foot
蟹堡王的匹萨
The Krusty Krab pizza
是你和我的匹萨
is the pizza for you and me
蟹堡王的匹萨
The Krusty Krab pizza
是你和
is the pizza
我的脚要疼死了
And my feet are killing me
海绵宝宝  你在干什么
SpongeBob, what are you doing?
这是老祖先的办法
It's an old pioneer trick
从前我在电影里看到的
I saw it in a movie once
海绵宝宝  没时间给你
SpongeBob, this is no time for
有用了
It's working
啥玩意
What is it?
卡车
Truck
十六轮的
16 wheels
我可以给你示范老祖先怎么打车的
Now I can show you how the pioneers hitchhiked
那个跳霹雳舞的  小心要撞上了
Crashin', frashin' break dancer
他要停船了
He's stopping
蟹堡王的匹萨
The Krusty Krab pizza
是你和我的匹萨
is the pizza for you and me
蟹堡王的匹萨
The Krusty Krab pizza
是我们外卖的匹萨
is the pizza we deliver-y
蟹堡王的匹萨
The Krusty Krab pizza
是特好吃的匹萨
is the pizza very tasty
能不能给我把那个笨匹萨放了
Will you let go of that stupid pizza already?
不能放  这是给客人的
I can't, It's for the customer
谁在乎什么客人
Who cares about the customer?
我在乎
I do
那我才不在乎
Well, I don't
章鱼哥
Squidward
放了那个匹萨
Let go of that pizza
不放
No
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
放了那个匹萨
Let go of the pizza
不放
No
这是给客人的
It's for the customer
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
放了那个匹萨
Let go of the pizza
不放
No
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
抓紧那个匹萨
Hang on to the pizza
路呢
Where's the road?
完蛋了
We're doomed
要走哪回去
How are we gonna get home?
往哪里走
Which way do we go?
要怎么办才好
What are we going to do now?
这边没路
There's no road here
我看要往这走才能到镇上
I think town's this way
[ 叶忒罗：《圣经》出埃及记中人物 ]
叶忒罗  你这该不会是
Don't tell me, Jethro
老祖先那学来的吗
The pioneers?
对了
That's right
青苔会指向文明
Moss always points to civilization
走那边
That way?
走那边就能到
That way there?
所以先让我弄清楚
So, let me get this straight
你说我们该要走那边
You think that we should go that way?
对
Yep
那我就走这边
Well, then I'm going this way
章鱼哥等等
Squid, wait
我觉得不应该
I don't think
相信我  我知道要走哪
Trust me, I know where I'm going
蟹堡王的匹萨
The Krusty Krab pizza
绝对就是匹萨
is the pizza absolutivally
匹萨
Pizza
蟹堡王的匹萨
The Krusty Krab pizza
是你和我的
is the pizza, yeah
匹
for you and
萨
me
王的匹萨
Krab Pizza
你和
for you
蟹
Krust
鞋包王的皮
the Krusshy and the
蟹的匹
Krab and the
里面的匹萨
pizza inside
海绵宝宝
Sponge
我们得吃东西
we've got to eat something
听说民不聊生时  老祖先会吃珊瑚
I heard in times of hardship
the pioneers would eat coral
不对  可能不是珊瑚
No, maybe it wasn't coral
可能是沙子
Maybe it was sand
不对不对  是泥巴
No, no-- mud
把匹萨给我
Give me the pizza
等下  我现在记起来了
Wait, I remember now--
就是珊瑚
It was coral
把匹萨给我
Give it to me
不给  已经保证说是给客人的了
No, we promised it's for the customer
你说得对
You're right
这是给客人的
It's for the customer
对啊
Yeah
也许最好要看一眼
Maybe we better check on it--
检查一下匹萨有没有事
Make sure it's okay
那个
Well
就只看一眼
Just a peek
看完了  匹萨没事
Okay, it's fine
不  我应该看到了什么东西
No, I think I saw something
没
Oh no--
我看错了
I was wrong
看起来应该没事
Looks okay
这匹萨长得可真是别致
Sure is a fine-looking pizza
对啊
Yeah
那什么东西
What's that?
是奶酪吗
Is that the cheese?
是啊
Yeah
还有辣香肠
And the pepperoni?
是啊
Yeah
看起来是不是很好吃
Looks good, huh?
等一下
Wait a second
我知道你要搞什么鬼了  章鱼哥
I know what you're trying to do, Squidward
我是不会让你吃掉匹萨的
I'm not letting you eat the pizza
把匹萨给我
Give me that pizza
不给
No
别逼我直接用抢的  海绵宝宝
Don't make me take it away from you, SpongeBob
快起开
Get away
给我回来  海绵宝宝
Get back here, SpongeBob
把匹萨给我
Give me that pizza
不给
No
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
不给
No
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
不给
No
等会
Wait
不给
No
我要那个匹萨
I want that pizza
你不管怎样都要把匹萨给我
And you're going to hand it over one way or another
快看  我们得救了
Look, we're saved
对  我们得救了
Sure, we're saved
现在把匹萨给我
Now give me some pizza
不
No
是真的  章鱼哥
Really, squid
我们得救了
We're saved
能给我消停会吗
Will you cut that out
得救了  得救了
Saved, saved
得得得得救了
Saved, saved, saved, saved, saved, saved
我们得救了
Saved, we are saved
那只是块垃圾巨岩
That's just a stupid boulder
不只是块巨岩
It's not just a boulder
还是石头
It's a rock
石头
A rock
是巨大美丽又古老的石头
It's a big, beautiful old rock
老祖先就用这些石头骑行了好几里远
The pioneers used to ride these babies for miles
而且这石头形态绝佳
And it's in great shape
海绵宝宝  能不能别扯什么笨祖先了
Will you forget the stupid pioneers?
有没有想过老祖先现在一个不剩了
Have you ever noticed that there are none of them left?
原因就在于他们打车技能差
That's because they were lousy hitchhikers
还吃珊瑚  还用海藻看方向
ate coral, and took directions from algae
现在你又跟我说
And now you're telling me
他们还可以开
they thought they could drive
石头
Rocks
你等等我  叶忒罗
Hold on there, Jethro
我等不及要看客人脸上的表情了
I can't wait to see the look on our customer's face
什么事
Yeah?
恭喜你先生
Congratulations, sir
你的蟹黄堡匹萨送到了
Your krabby patty pizza's here
谢谢了
Thanks
我一直都很想要来一份
I've been dying for one of these
特
It
我饮料呢
Where's my drink?
什么饮料
What drink?
我饮料呢
My drink
我无糖海草水呢
My Diet Dr Kelp
别跟我说你忘记送饮料来了
Don't tell me you forgot my drink
可是  你根本就没有点
But you didn't order any
没有饮料我还吃什么匹萨
How am I supposed to eat this pizza without my drink?
可是
But
你就没有给顾客着想过吗
Didn't you ever once think of the customer?
你就这水平都能叫外卖员
You call yourself a delivery boy?
那老子不买了
Well, I ain't buying
海绵宝宝
Sponge?
没事的
It's okay
海绵宝宝
Sponge
Sponge?
怎么又来一个
Another one?
听好  老子跟你同伴说了不付匹萨钱
Look, I told your little friend I ain't paying for that
我这份免费送
Well, this one's on the house
他改主意了
Did he change his mind?
当然了
He sure did
一口就把匹萨给吃掉了
Ate the whole thing in one bite
没配饮料
No drink?
没配
No
现在带我回家去吧
Now take me home
开玩笑吧
Are you kidding?
还有足够时间回去上班呢
We have just enough time to make it back to work
上班
Work?
我爪子好疼
My aching tentacles
大菠萝
甜蜜的家
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
走
Walking
饿
Hungry
还是饿
Still hungry
死线虫
Dang nematodes
渴
Thirsty
小蜗
万岁  小蜗
Hurray, gary
我们终于变大了
We're finally huge
等一下
Wait a minute
不好
Oh, no
贝壳电话
Shell phone
有了
I know
打电话给章鱼哥
I'll call Squidward
他知道要怎么办
He'll know what to do
喂
Hello?
章鱼哥
Squidward
给我搞破坏的时间到了吗
Is it time already for you to ruin my day?
章鱼哥  快来帮忙
Squidward, help me
我房子在变小
My house is shrinking
一大早起来
And I woke up this morning
房子整个越变越小
and it was getting smaller and smaller
墙都要挤到我了
The walls are closing in on me
小蜗也被吓着了
Gary is terrified too
不好了
Oh, no
真好啊
Yep, it is
给章鱼哥搞破坏的时间到了吗
Is it time already to ruin Squid's day?
海绵宝宝  别丢下我一个人开搞
SpongeBob, don't start without me
线虫
Nematodes
我家剩下来的就只有这颗小石子了
The only thing left in my house is this little pebble
这都怎么了
What's going on here?
各位  我有个坏消息
I've got bad news, guys
快看我家怎么了
Look at what happened to my house
消失了
It's gone
都消失了
It's all gone
我要怎么办
What am I going to do?
我要去哪住
Where am I going to live?
好啊
Yeah
海绵宝宝  你家消失了
SpongeBob, your house is gone
怎么说才好
Well, what can I say?
认识你可真高兴  海绵宝宝
It's been great knowing you, SpongeBob
祝你到别处好运
Good luck somewhere else
我会想你的
I'm going to miss you
章鱼哥好难接受这件事
Squid's taking it real hard
所以你现在要怎么办
What are you going to do now?
我看我得搬回去跟爸妈住
I guess I'll have to move back with my mom and dad
爸妈
不行  等一下
No, wait a minute--
可以不用搬
No, you don't
爸妈
咱可以给你盖新房子
We can build you a new house
房子咱盖不了
We can't build a house
好啦  很简单的
Well, sure, it's easy
我房子就是自己一个人盖的
I built my house all by myself
那就好  派大星
All right, Patrick
来开工吧
Let's get to work
完工了
We're done
是啊
Yeah
你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
真希望能住进去
I wish I lived there
真的吗
Really?
假的
No
一室
One bedroom
真该死
Tartar sauce
好像我们只能回去跟爸妈住了
Well, looks like we've got to move back with mom and pop
不可以搬回去跟爸妈住
You can't move back in with your parents
我爸妈把我给赶出家门那会
When my parents kicked me out of the house
我就从来没回去过
I never went back
等下
Wait
你跟小蜗可以来跟我一起住
You and Gary can come stay with me
那就太好了
That'd be great
对
Yeah
我们就要变石友了
We'll be rockmates
晚安  海绵宝宝
Good night, SpongeBob
晚安  石友
Good night, rockmate
晚安  小蜗
Good night, Gary
搞什
What the
有蜘蛛
Spiders
蜘蛛
快弄下来
Get them off me
弄下来
Get them off
醒过来
Wake up
别打了  是我
No, it's me
我是海绵宝宝
I'm SpongeBob
蜘蛛
Spider
快弄下来
Get them off me
章鱼哥
Squidward
怎么了
What?
章鱼哥
Squidward
我们能在这待几天或者一两个月吗
Could we stay here a couple of days or a month or two?
能吧  随便吧
Yeah, well, whatever
谢谢了
Thanks
谢谢了  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squidward
章鱼哥  可不可以移到旁边去一点
Squidward, can you scoot over a little?
可以的
Yeah, sure
能不能顺便给我拿杯水来
Well, while you're at it, can you get me a glass of water?
好的
Okay
能吧
Yeah, sure
你家真的好舒服
Yeah, this is a real swell place you've got here
谢谢了  兄弟
Thanks, buddy
不用谢
You're welcome
我好喜欢到别人家过夜
Yeah, I like sleep-overs
是啊
Yeah
我也喜欢
Me, too
是啊  真的棒
Yep, this is great
晚安章鱼哥
Good night, Squidward
晚安  海绵宝宝
Good night, SpongeBob
今天是个好日子  章鱼哥
Today's the big day, Squidward
可别迟到了
Don't want to be late
得赶紧的
Got to hurry
等下
Hold it
都给我等下
Hold everything
我可不想错过这场好戏
I would not want to miss this--
海绵宝宝今天就要搬走了
The day SpongeBob moves
真不敢相信这事真的发生了
I can't believe it's really happening
别担心了  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
我会回来看你的
I'll come visit you
不用安慰我了  海绵宝宝
Don't try to cheer me up, SpongeBob
我求你了
Please
我爸妈来了
Here come my parents
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
乖宝贝好  我们来了
Hi, honey, we're here
快上车  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
儿子你要赶紧的
Hurry, hurry, son
你妈把饭都做好了
Your mother has dinner waiting
老妈好
Hi, mom
海绵妈妈好
Hello, Mrs. SquarePants
我来帮你们提行李
Let me help you with these bags
等我一会儿
Just give me a minute
我再也留不住你了  小石子
I cannot hold on to you any longer, little pebble
你留下了好多的回忆
You hold too many memories
章鱼哥
Well, Squidward
就此再会吧
This is good-bye
再见了  海绵宝宝
Good-bye, SpongeBob
再见了
Good-bye
再见  海绵宝宝
Good-bye, SpongeBob
再见了
Bye-bye-bye
再见了  海绵宝宝
Good-bye, SpongeBob
再见  再见
Good-bye, good-bye
快上车  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
再见了  派大星
Good-bye, Patrick
再见了  裤头村
Good-bye, Bikini Bottom
海绵宝宝要走了
SpongeBob is leaving
要走了  要走了
He's leaving, he's leaving
是的宝贝儿
Yeah, baby
海绵宝宝要走了
SpongeBob is leaving
要走了
He's leaving
我家回来了
My house is back
我的菠萝屋啊
Good old pineapple
就刚好在原先的地方
It was exactly where it used to be
章鱼哥你说好不好
Squidward, isn't this great?
我再也不走了
I'm back forever
再也不走了
Forever?